Hello.
Welcome back.
In this lesson, we are going to see how to configure our SDM 32 microcontroller for time interrupt.
Let's get started.
I've created a new project and cleared all pin out.
In this example, we simply going to use time.
Materne We've got a number of times.
Oh, just select time or 10 from here and then expand this.
And then for time attent, all we have to do is select, activate for other times we would have to select
the Channel one, Channel two, if other times I can, to what are connected to multiple channels.
But Time ten is simple compared to other times.
So all we do.
Yes, click active.
And to make the experiment interesting, we can enable our GPL you for the LCD so that we can toco the
LCD for this P five, this word new clue.
It is connected.
If you're using a different board, you can use it to discover your LCD.
So I can look to the around PD 12, 13, 14 and 15.
So select the new clue early.
So this is GPL, your output like this.
And the clock configuration here in order to allow this example to run on all of the F four boards with
almost no almost no customization or change.
I'm going to set the clock configuration, which is the default for the estimated two four zero board,
minus four one one.
If I select this is the default that shows up.
So I'm going to select HSR here.
And then this will become sixteen and I'm going to pass here sixteen so that we all have the same clock.
Even if you have Air Force, you're at one.
Right.
So as we can see, a sixteen Mucke maximum clock and all of our Air Force here have 60 megahertz clock,
including our timer.
That will be used.
So we would apply pre-schooler to this 60 megahertz if we wanted to bring down the clock frequency.
So now we can go ahead and configure our timer or come to penult here and then Time or 10 is selected.
I'll explain this and then I'll come to the parameter.
Stop over here.
So over here we can scale down our time.
I remember our time.
A clock is 16 megahertz.
If we divide 16 by 1000, we get, um.
If we divide 16 megahertz by 1000, we get 16000, which is sixteen kilohertz.
So I'll come here and divide by 1000.
But because the count starts from zero to right to 1000, you have to put nine nine nine because you
can't zero through nine nine nine and this will give you 1000 steps.
So what we left with now is sixteen thousand.
So we can further divide this to get.
We want to scale down our clock to one second to sixteen thousand.
I'm going to divide the 16000 by sixteen thousand, which I'll pass up to this count up here.
Right here.
So if I pass sixteen thousand here.
Now my clock will be out one second.
Our clock frequency is at um.
That's what we saw is sixteen megahertz.
And we started by dividing the 16 megahertz by 1000.
So 60 megahertz means 16 million.
We divide a 16 million by 1000.
We get 16000.
So when we get here, we divide us sixteen thousand by sixteen thousand.
And then we end up with one, which is one second.
So I said, because we count from zero 1000, we have to write nine hundred and ninety nine in the same
way.
Sixteen thousand.
We have to write fifteen thousand and ninety nine.
Fifteen thousand.
Nine hundred and ninety nine.
Like this.
Right.
Over here, we can enable you to preload.
And because we will use an interrupt, we can come to NVC here and enable the interrupt for all time.
We said we're doing time.
I interrupt experiment.
Right.
So we can go ahead and generally tell code.
I'll come over here.
Generate code.
And then I'll give this a name.
Time to interrupt.
Timer on the score.
Interrupt.
And then also later to change the to Kubota e an hour click here to generate.
So that's the project of cleaned up a bit of the comment.
So that's what we have.
And if you're going to look at our timer in it, it's got all these elections.
We made our period.
Our priest.
And then all of them.
And if you go to the, um, the I.T. is competitive for I.T. Dossie file, you realize the uninterrupted
love was created for our time.
There should be an interrupt handler down here for a timer.
It's a timer one up to time 10.
I RCU handler terma one up.
OK.
Right.
So we can start our tolima.
We started time off with interrupt and then you know when we always deal and we interrupt, we've to
implement the callback function.
So when we started the timer we go to the um the timer module, which is the time that C file and copy
the callback function and bring it here to implement it.
So we go into C hole on the score.
T I am on this call base on the score start on the score.
I.T. we start in with interrupt.
So we need to pass the address of the time.
A handler which is h t i m 10 like this.
So we can go and fetch our Kobuk.
Oh, come over here to our drivers and then haul driver the source over here.
I am not see fall.
Where is it?
It's over here.
And I'll say no.
And I'm going to search on the score, on the score.
Which keyword?
And this will show me all the callback functions available and I'll find the appropriate one.
We don't want this one.
We want, though, the callback that would deal with periodic laps such that the time period that we
set, when it passes, when it's elapses, we want to do something.
Both want to experiment with other callback functions.
Certainly you can try them out.
So over here we have period half complete callback and then we have period have we have period elapsed,
half complete callback and then we have period elapsed callback.
So if the period that we set, if half it's in the middle and we want to run that particular block of
code.
We can use this callback here.
But if the period is completely a lapse and want to run a block of growth, we use that period elapsed
callback, which a copy from here.
And I'll come to my middle C file over here.
And then I'll put it up here and we know what we want to do.
It period elapsed in our experiment.
We simply going to talk a lower LCD.
But like, you know, in the interrupt service routine, you can do whatever you want in there.
So basically is a classic do somethin.
So over here, I will do something.
It's not on our rhythm, it's basically talking in the early days.
So I'll see how on school to peel you on this score.
Period.
Lost.
Um, sorry.
Hall underscored GPA.
You, uh, it should be toggled ality.
Goodness I'm losing my mind.
And then the is GPL you.
And then we know is GPL you pin five over here.
This is where a one nucleo LCD connected.
If you're using a different board you've got to select the appropriate port and the appropriate pin.
Um we can go ahead and build our projects, our clinic over here to build.
It's built successfully.
We can go to the debugger, click over here to bug.
Okay.
And we don't need anything from the watch window or the expressions for you.
Oh, we have to do is click here to run.
And my LCD is blinking, and I hope yours was blinking as well.
It's totally up to one Hertz rate, which is one second rate, just like we said, a wire timer.
So this or the rest full time.
I interrupt, like I said, and the interrupt, you can do whatever you want at the rate of the period,
the time period.
I you said if you want a block of code to execute every second, you can write to that block of code
here.
If you wanted a block of code to execute every five seconds, every 10 milliseconds, every hundred
milliseconds, you can set the time a clock appropriately and put that block of code in the period elapsed
callback.
And in the same way, if you want a different block of code to to execute half this period we saw that
there is that period have elapsed callback to that would allow us to execute something when it is half
of the period we set.
Right.
So this or the rest.
And I'll see you later.
Organize the.